<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>vanbuncha - education</title>
    <subtitle>Personal site for documenting projects and blogging stuff.</subtitle>
    <link href="https://vanguyen.info/tags/education/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://vanguyen.info"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://vanguyen.info/tags/education/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>42 Prague experience</title>
        <published>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://vanguyen.info/blog/42experience/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://vanguyen.info/blog/42experience/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-42&quot;&gt;What is 42&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-is-42&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-is-42&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;42 is a global network of tuition-free, peer-to-peer coding schools that is revolutionizing the way people learn how to code. Founded in France in 2013, 42 has since expanded to more than 20 locations around the world, including the United States, Russia, Morocco, and the Czech Republic. At 42, there are no traditional teachers or lectures. Instead, students work collaboratively on coding projects and provide feedback to each other to develop their skills. This unique approach to education is designed to be adaptable to the rapidly changing demands of the tech industry and encourages students to become self-directed learners and problem solvers. With its innovative curriculum, flexible learning environment, and global reach, 42 is paving the way for the next generation of coders.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;personal-experience&quot;&gt;Personal experience&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#personal-experience&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: personal-experience&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently completed the 42 piscine, a four-week intensive coding bootcamp offered by the 42 network. Throughout the program, I dove deep into the world of C programming, learning the language from scratch. One of the best things about the piscine was participating in the exams, which sometimes lasted for five hours or more. While it may sound like a lot of time, the exams flew by as they were incredibly challenging and rewarding. Additionally, I discovered a newfound appreciation for vim, a powerful text editor that became my go-to tool throughout the program. Overall, the 42 piscine taught me not only the fundamentals of C programming but also the importance of perseverance, collaboration, and a willingness to learn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#conclusion&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: conclusion&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite successfully completing the 42 piscine and being accepted into the full program, I ultimately decided not to pursue further education with 42. While I enjoyed the unique learning environment and the camaraderie of my fellow students, I realized that the peer-to-peer approach wasn&#x27;t the best fit for me. I found that I learn better in a more structured environment with traditional teachers and lectures. Despite this, I am grateful for the experience and the valuable skills I gained during the piscine. The program pushed me out of my comfort zone and forced me to develop new problem-solving and collaboration skills, which will undoubtedly be useful in my future career endeavors. Ultimately, I think 42 is an incredible institution that is changing the way people learn how to code, and I have the utmost respect for its innovative approach to education.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;example&quot;&gt;Example&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#example&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: example&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;









    



    
    
    

    
        
        
        
        
        
    

&lt;figure class=&quot;extended-figure&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;vanguyen.info&amp;#x2F;processed_images&amp;#x2F;example_exercise.4e648c1f719531e7.png&quot; class=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Example from C07&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Example from C07&lt;&#x2F;figcaption&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-takeaways&quot;&gt;Key takeaways&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#key-takeaways&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: key-takeaways&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Norminette is always right.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim is supreme tool.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By Odin, by Thor! Use your Brain !!!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
