<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>vanbuncha - software</title>
	<subtitle>personal site</subtitle>
	<link href="https://vanguyen.info/categories/software/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://vanguyen.info"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://vanguyen.info/categories/software/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Public website</title>
		<published>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://vanguyen.info/projects/zola-project/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://vanguyen.info/projects/zola-project/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Public website with self-hosting&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;h1 id=&quot;deploying-my-website-onto-a-raspberry-pi-with-apache-server-using-cloudflare-and-ssg-zola&quot;&gt;Deploying My Website onto a Raspberry Pi with Apache Server using Cloudflare and SSG Zola&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, fellow tech enthusiasts! In this blog post, I&#x27;m excited to share my experience of deploying my website onto a Raspberry Pi with Apache server using Cloudflare and SSG Zola.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get started, I should note that I&#x27;m not a web development expert. However, I love tinkering with technology and learning new things, and that&#x27;s how I ended up taking on this challenge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-apache-server&quot;&gt;Installing Apache Server&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, I made sure that my Raspberry Pi was up-to-date with the latest software updates. Next, I installed Apache server on the Pi by running the following command in the terminal:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#x27;sudo apt-get install apache2&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Apache was up and running, I tested it out by typing the IP address of the Raspberry Pi into a web browser. Lo and behold, the Apache default page was displayed!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Configuring My Router and DNS
Next, I had to configure my router to forward incoming traffic to the Raspberry Pi and set up a dynamic DNS service to map my IP address to a domain name. I chose to use a service called no-ip.com, which provides free dynamic DNS.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;installing-ssg-zola&quot;&gt;Installing SSG Zola&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Apache and DNS set up, I was ready to install SSG Zola, a static site generator. I used SSG Zola to create a simple website in Markdown language. Once the site was ready, I used the zola build command to generate the static HTML files for my website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;uploading-my-site-to-the-raspberry-pi&quot;&gt;Uploading My Site to the Raspberry Pi&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my website built, it was time to upload the generated files to the Raspberry Pi using SFTP. I used FileZilla, an open-source FTP client, to connect to the Raspberry Pi and upload the files to the &#x2F;var&#x2F;www&#x2F;html directory. This directory is the default web root for Apache server on Debian-based Linux distributions like Raspberry Pi OS.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-ssl-encryption-with-cloudflarxe&quot;&gt;Adding SSL Encryption with Cloudflarxe&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, my website was live, but it wasn&#x27;t secure and didn&#x27;t have an SSL certificate. To address this, I used Cloudflare, a free DNS and CDN service, to add SSL encryption to my website.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I signed up for a free account on Cloudflare and added my domain name to the service. Cloudflare provided me with two new DNS servers, which I then updated on no-ip.com. After waiting for the DNS records to propagate, I enabled the SSL encryption feature on Cloudflare, and voila! My website was now secure and had a green padlock icon in the web browser.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deploying my website onto a Raspberry Pi with Apache server using Cloudflare and SSG Zola was a fun and educational experience. It allowed me to learn more about web development, Linux administration, and networking. I hope that sharing my experience will inspire others to tinker with technology and explore new horizons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare and SSG Zola in Markdown language was a fun and educational experience. It allowed me to learn more about web development, Linux administration, and networking. I hope that sharing my experience will inspire others to tinker with technology and explore new horizons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
